Some things were never meant to be controlled.
Geostorm is a action, science fiction, thriller film directed by Dean Devlin.
After an unprecedented series of natural disasters threatened the planet, the world's leaders came together to
create an intricate network of satellites to control the global climate and keep everyone safe.
But now, something has gone wrong: the system built to protect Earth is attacking it, and it becomes a race against the
clock to uncover the real threat before a worldwide geostorm wipes out everything and everyone along with it.
Jake Lawson, played by Gerard Butler.
Ute Fassbinder, played by Alexandra Maria Lara.
Max Lawson, played by Jim Sturgess.
U.S. Secret Service Agent Sarah Wilson, played by Abbie Cornish.
U.S. Secretary of State Leonard Dekkom, played by Ed Harris.
U.S. President Andrew Palma, played by Andy Garcia.
Geostorm is a 2017 American science-fiction disaster film directed, cowritten,
and coproduced by Dean Devlin (in his feature directorial debut).
The film stars Gerard Butler, Jim Sturgess, Abbie
Cornish, Ed Harris, and Andy García.
It follows a satellite designer who tries to save the world from a storm of epic
proportions caused by malfunctioning climate-controlling satellites.
Principal photography began on October 20, 2014, in New Orleans, Louisiana.
After poor test screenings, reshoots took place in December 2016 under executive producer
Jerry Bruckheimer, writer Laeta Kalogridis, and new director Danny Cannon.
To date, the film is the only co-production
between Skydance Media and Warner Bros.
Geostorm was released in the United States on October 20, 2017, in all formats, and heavily underperformed at the box
office, grossing only $221.6 million worldwide against a $120–130 million budget, losing Warner Bros.
$71.6 million.
The film was also widely panned by critics for its muddled storytelling,
underdeveloped characters and lackluster visual effects.
The film explores themes of future, artificial intelligence
(a.i.), weather manipulation, end of the world, murder.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.